Guide to the American Song Sheets Collection, circa 1830s-1920s, bulk 1850s-1880s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
American Song Sheets collection circa 1830s-1920s bulk 1850s-1880s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
3.0 Linear Feet 1982 Items
In the mid nineteenth century, publishers printed the lyrics to popular songs, without their tunes, on small sheets called song sheets, handbills, or broadsides. These sheets were often illustrated with a woodcut scene or portrait and sold at gathering places where people sang together.
Duke's collection of American song sheets includes 1,982 of these ephemeral productions, from "The Star Spangled Banner" to "Pop Goes the Weasel," forming a rich source for research on American society and culture. The American South and the Civil War era are especially well documented, including well over one hundred Confederate broadsides. The collection also includes carrier's addresses, non-musical poetry, and other ephemeral verse. Publishers represented in the collection include: J. Andrews, A. W. Auner, Bell and Company, James D. Gray, Johnson and Company, Charles Magnus, H. de Marsan, T. M. Scroggy, St. Clair Smith, John T. Thorne, H. J. Wehman, J. Wrigley, and others.
Administrative Information
Online Items
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available in: American Song Sheets - Duke Digital Collections
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The American Song Sheets Collection were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library through several small purchases. Some song sheets were removed from other manuscript collections. Portions of this collection were formerly known as the Broadside Verse collection.
Historical Note
In the mid nineteenth century, publishers printed the lyrics to popular songs, without their tunes, on small sheets called song sheets, handbills, or broadsides. These sheets were often illustrated with a woodcut scene or portrait and sold at gathering places where people sang together.
Collection Overview
Duke's collection of American song sheets includes around 1,982 of these ephemeral productions, from The Star Spangled Banner to Pop Goes the Weasel, forming a rich source for research on American society and culture. The American South and the Civil War era are especially well documented, including well over one hundred Confederate broadsides. The collection also includes carrier's addresses, non-musical poetry, and other ephemeral verse. Publishers represented in the collection include: J. Andrews, A. W. Auner, Bell and Company, James D. Gray, Johnson and Company, Charles Magnus, H. de Marsan, T. M. Scroggy, St. Clair Smith, John T. Thorne, H. J. Wehman, J. Wrigley, and others.
Note that some song sheets are housed in the Confederate Pamphlet collection and the Broadsides collection.
Images and full-text of digitized song sheets are available at: http://library.duke.edu/digitalcollections/songsheets/
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
American poetry -- 19th century
American songs -- 19th century
A.W. Auner (Firm: Philadelphia, Pa.)
Charles Magnus & Co
Confederate States of America -- Songs and music
De Marsan, H. (Henry)
Johnson, J. H. (John H.)
Music -- United States -- History -- 19th century
United States -- History -- Civil War 1861-1865 -- Poetry
United States -- History -- Civil War 1861-1865 -- Songs and music
Wehman, Henry J.
Broadsides
Related Material
America Singing: Nineteenth-Century Song Sheets
Library of Congress
Historic American Sheet Music
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Separated Material
Some song sheets are shelved in the Confederate Pamphlet collection (items 1719-1741) and the Broadsides collection (items 1742-1769). Call numbers for these items are noted.
Contents of Collection
- American Song Sheets, circa 1850s-1880s, (4 boxes, items 1-1608)
  Chiefly song sheets documenting the Civil War and the American South. Some song sheets have been cataloged individually. Digitized song sheets are numbered
  - Abraham's Daughter (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Abraham's Daughter (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Abraham's Daughter (Box 1, Item 3)
  - After the Battle, Mother (Box 1, Item 4)
  - America (Box 1, Item 5)
  - America (Box 1, Item 6)
  - American Liberty (Box 1, Item 7)
  - The American Star! (Box 1, Item 8)
  - American Star (Box 1, Item 9)
  - The American Star (Box 1, Item 10)
  - The American Star (Box 1, Item 11)
  - The American Star (Box 1, Item 12)
  - The American Volunteer (Box 1, Item 13)
  - Angel's Whisper (Box 1, Item 14)
  - Answer to Mother (Box 1, Item 15)
  - Answer to Who Will Care for Mother Now? (Box 1, Item 16)
  - Any Other Man (Box 1, Item 17)
  - Any Other Man No. 2 (Box 1, Item 18)
  - An Appeal for Maryland (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Arab Steed (Box 1, Item 20a)
  - The Soldier's Reveille (Box 1, Item 20b)
  - Arab Steed (Box 1, Item 21)
  - Are We Free? (Box 1, Item 22)
  - The Army of Liberty (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Assassination of Ellsworth (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Attention (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Away Down South There Is Rebellion (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Babylon is Fallen (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Babylon is Fallen (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Baltimore Union Song! (Box 1, Item 29)
  - The Banner of the Free (Box 1, Item 30)
  - The Banner of the Sea (Box 1, Item 31)
  - The Banner of the Sea (Box 1, Item 32)
  - The Battle at Charleston Harbor (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Battle Cry of Freedom, or, We'll Rally Round the Flag, Boys (Box 1, Item 34)
  - The Battle-cry of Freedom (Box 1, Item 35)
  - The Battle-cry of Freedom! (Box 1, Item 36)
  - The Battle-cry of Freedom! (Box 1, Item 37)
  - Battle Cry of the Pennsylvania Reserves (Box 1, Item 38a)
  - Keystone Brigade (Box 1, Item 38b)
  - The Battle Eve (Box 1, Item 39)
  - The Battle Eve (Box 1, Item 40)
  - Battle-Hymn of the Republic (Box 1, Item 41)
  - The Battle is O'er (Box 1, Item 42)
  - Battle of Bull Run (Box 1, Item 43)
  - Battle of Bull Run (Box 1, Item 44)
  - Battle of Bull Run (Box 1, Item 45)
  - Battle of Bull Run (Box 1, Item 46)
  - Battle of Bull's Run (Box 1, Item 47)
  - Battle of Cedar Creek (Box 1, Item 48)
  - The Battle of Fort Macon (Box 1, Item 49)
  - The Battle of Kinston (Box 1, Item 50)
  - Battle of Leesburgh (Box 1, Item 51)
  - Battle of Spotsylvania (Box 1, Item 52)
  - Battle of Spotsylvania (Box 1, Item 53)
  - The Battle of the Wilderness (Box 1, Item 54)
  - The Battle Song of the Maryland Line (Box 1, Item 55)
  - Be My Mother Till I Die (Box 1, Item 56)
  - Be True to Our Flag (Box 1, Item 57)
  - Beauregard's Bells (Box 1, Item 58)
  - Lizzie Fane (Box 1, Item 59a)
  - Minnie Clyde, Kitty Clyde's Sister (Box 1, Item 59b)
  - Ben M'Culloch (Box 1, Item 60)
  - Berdan's Sharpshooters (Box 1, Item 61)
  - Bid Me Good-bye, or the Soldier's Farewell (Box 1, Item 62)
  - Bid Me Good-bye, or the Soldier's Farewell (Box 1, Item 63)
  - Bid Me Good-bye, or the Soldier's Farewell (Box 1, Item 64)
  - Billy Barlow (Box 1, Item 65)
  - Billy Barlow (Box 1, Item 66)
  - Billy Wilson's Zouaves (Box 1, Item 67)
  - The Black Regiment (Box 1, Item 68)
  - Bless the Lips that Kissed our Darling (Box 1, Item 69)
  - Bless the Lips that Kissed our Darling (Box 1, Item 70)
  - The Blue and the Gray (Box 1, Item 71)
  - The Blue Devils or the National Zouaves (Box 1, Item 72)
  - The Blue Devils or the National Zouaves (Box 1, Item 73)
  - Bob Anderson (Box 1, Item 74)
  - The Bold Engineer (Box 1, Item 75)
  - The Bonnie Blue Flag (Box 1, Item 76)
  - Bonnie Blue Flag (Box 1, Item 77)
  - Bonnie Blue Flag (Box 1, Item 78)
  - Bonnie Blue Flag (Box 1, Item 79)
  - The Bonny Green Flag (Box 1, Item 80)
  - A Boquet for Our Maggie (Box 1, Item 81)
  - A Boquet for Our Maggie (Box 1, Item 82)
  - Bounty-Jumper (Box 1, Item 83)
  - The Bowld Sojer Boy (Box 1, Item 84)
  - Bowld Sojer Boy (Box 1, Item 85)
  - Brave Boys (Box 1, Item 86)
  - Brave Boys Are They (Box 1, Item 87)
  - Brave Boys Are They (Box 1, Item 88)
  - Brave Boys Are They (Box 1, Item 89)
  - Bring My Brother Back to Me (Box 1, Item 90)
  - The Broker's "Stamp Act" Lament (Box 1, Item 91)
  - Brother's Fainting at the Door (Box 1, Item 92)
  - Brother's Fainting at the Door (Box 1, Item 93)
  - Brother's Fainting at the Door (Box 1, Item 94)
  - Brownell The Gallant Zouave (Box 1, Item 95)
  - Bummers, Come and Meet Us (Box 1, Item 96)
  - Bully For You (Box 1, Item 97)
  - By the Sad Potomac Shore, or The Death of Col. Baker (Box 1, Item 98)
  - C.S.A. to G.A.R. A Waif on the Past (Box 1, Item 99)
  - The Call! (Box 1, Item 100)
  - Call the Boys of '76 (Box 1, Item 101)
  - Call the Boys of '76 (Box 1, Item 102)
  - Camp Gals (Box 1, Item 103)
  - A Campaign Song (Box 1, Item 104)
  - The Capture of Jeff Davis (Box 1, Item 105)
  - The Capture of Jeff Davis (Box 1, Item 106)
  - The Capture of Jeff Davis (Box 1, Item 107)
  - The Capture of Jeff Davis (Box 1, Item 108)
  - Capture of Sally Davis (Box 1, Item 109)
  - Capture of Sally Davis (Box 1, Item 110)
  - The Carrier's New Year Address, to the Patrons of "The Cartridge Box" (Box 1, Item 111)
  - The Charge at Roanoke (Box 1, Item 112)
  - Charming Lizzie Clay (Box 1, Item 113)
  - Cheer, Boys, Cheer for Next November (Box 1, Item 114)
  - Cheer, Boys, Cheer for Next November (Box 1, Item 115)
  - Cheer Up, Sam! or Sarah Bell (Box 1, Item 116)
  - Chief Justice Taney (Box 1, Item 117)
  - Chivalrous C.S.A! (Box 1, Item 118)
  - The Christian Soldier (Box 1, Item 119)
  - Cling to the Union (Box 1, Item 120)
  - Cling to the Union (Box 1, Item 121)
  - Cling to the Union (Box 1, Item 122)
  - The Coal Black Steed (Box 1, Item 123)
  - Col. Owens' Gallant Irish Volunteers (Box 1, Item 124)
  - The Colored Brigade (Box 1, Item 125)
  - Colored Gemman In de Army (Box 1, Item 126)
  - The Colored Soldier Boy! (Box 1, Item 127)
  - Colored Volunteer (Box 1, Item 128)
  - Columbia Rules the Sea (Box 1, Item 129)
  - Columbia Shall Be Free (Box 1, Item 130)
  - Columbia, the Gem of the Ocean (Box 1, Item 131)
  - Columbia! The Hope of the World (Box 1, Item 132)
  - Columbia's Glorious Banner (Box 1, Item 133)
  - Columbia's Glorious Banner (Box 1, Item 134)
  - Columbia's Glory (Box 1, Item 135)
  - Come, Jeff, Come or Fort Donaldson is Taken (Box 1, Item 136)
  - Comrades, Join the Reveille (Box 1, Item 137)
  - The Confederate Flag (Box 1, Item 138)
  - Congressman Ely. (Box 1, Item 139)
  - Conscript's Lay (Box 1, Item 140)
  - The Constitution! (Box 1, Item 141)
  - The Constitution, Our Platform! McClellan, Our Choice! (Box 1, Item 142)
  - Old Shady (Box 1, Item 143)
  - Corcoran to his Regiment. Or "I Would Not Take Parole." (Box 1, Item 144)
  - Corcoran to his Regiment. Or "I Would Not Take Parole." (Box 1, Item 145)
  - Corcoran to his Regiment. Or "I Would Not Take Parole." (Box 1, Item 146)
  - Corcoran's Irish Legion (Box 1, Item 147)
  - Corcoran's Irish Legion (Box 1, Item 148a)
  - Comic Parody (Box 1, Item 148b)
  - Corporal Kelly (Box 1, Item 149)
  - The Craven (Box 1, Item 150)
  - Cumberland's Crew (Box 1, Item 151)
  - "Da Vis!" (Box 1, Item 152)
  - Darkey Conscript. (Box 1, Item 153)
  - Davis, Beauregard & Co (Box 1, Item 154)
  - Dear Mother, I've Come Home to Die. (Box 1, Item 155)
  - Dear Mother, I've Come Home to Eat. (Box 1, Item 156)
  - Death of Colonel Ellsworth (Box 1, Item 157)
  - Death of Col. Ellsworth (Box 1, Item 158)
  - Death of Col. Elmer E. Ellsworth (Box 1, Item 159)
  - Death of Col. Elmer E. Ellsworth (Box 1, Item 160)
  - Death of Col. Elmer E. Ellsworth (Box 1, Item 161)
  - The Death of Ellsworth (Box 1, Item 162)
  - The Debt (Box 1, Item 163)
  - Death of General Lyon (Box 1, Item 164)
  - The Debt of Maryland (Box 1, Item 165)
  - The Debt of Maryland (Box 1, Item 166)
  - The Declaration (Box 1, Item 167)
  - The Departure of the 69th Volunteers (Box 1, Item 168)
  - The Departure of the 69th Volunteers (Box 1, Item 169)
  - The Despot's Song! (Box 1, Item 170)
  - Disgrace & Shame (Box 1, Item 171)
  - Dividing Creek Volunteers (Box 1, Item 172)
  - Dixie. Where is Dixie? (Box 1, Item 173)
  - Dixey's Land (Box 1, Item 174)
  - Dixie for the Union (Box 1, Item 175)
  - Dixie for the Union (Box 1, Item 176)
  - The Dixie of our Union (Box 1, Item 177)
  - The Dixie of our Union (Box 1, Item 178)
  - Dixie's Land No. 3 (Box 1, Item 179)
  - Dixie's Land (Box 1, Item 180)
  - Dixie's Land (Box 1, Item 181)
  - Dixie's Nurse (Box 1, Item 182)
  - Dixie's Sunny Land (Box 1, Item 183)
  - Dixey's Conundrums (Box 1, Item 184)
  - Do They Think of Me at Home (Box 1, Item 185)
  - Dodge's Police (Box 1, Item 186)
  - The Dog is Dead (Box 1, Item 187)
  - Down-Trodden Maryland (Box 1, Item 188)
  - Down-Trodden Maryland (Box 1, Item 189)
  - Down Trodden Maryland (Box 1, Item 190)
  - Down Upon the Rappahannock (Box 1, Item 191)
  - Down Upon the Rappahannock (Box 1, Item 192)
  - The Draft is a Coming (Box 1, Item 193)
  - The Drummer Boy of Vicksburg (Box 1, Item 194)
  - The Dying Californian (Box 1, Item 195)
  - The Dying Hero's Request (Box 1, Item 196)
  - Dying Hero's Request (Box 1, Item 197)
  - The Dying Soldier (Box 1, Item 198)
  - The Dying Soldier to his Mother (Box 1, Item 199)
  - E Pluribus Unum (Box 1, Item 200)
  - E Pluribus Unum (Box 1, Item 201)
  - E Pluribus Unum (Box 1, Item 202)
  - E Pluribus Unum (Box 1, Item 203)
  - E Pluribus Unum (Box 1, Item 204)
  - Ellsworth Avengers (Box 1, Item 205)
  - Ellsworth Avengers (Box 1, Item 206)
  - Ellsworth Avengers (Box 1, Item 207)
  - Ellsworth, The Gallant Zouave (Box 1, Item 208)
  - Ellsworth's Avengers! (Box 1, Item 209)
  - Ellsworth's Avengers (Box 1, Item 210)
  - Ellsworth's Body Lies Mouldering in the Grave (Box 1, Item 211)
  - Ellsworth's Body Lies Mouldering in the Grave (Box 1, Item 212)
  - Enlisting Soldiers (Box 1, Item 213)
  - The Exiled Soldier's Adieu to Maryland (Box 1, Item 214)
  - The Exiled Soldier's Adieu to Maryland (Box 1, Item 215)
  - The Exodus (Box 1, Item 216)
  - The Fall of Charleston! (Box 1, Item 217)
  - Farragut's Ball (Box 1, Item 218)
  - Farragut's Ball (Box 1, Item 219)
  - The Father of Freedom (Box 1, Item 220)
  - The Federal Vendue (Box 1, Item 221)
  - "Fighting Joe Hooker." (Box 1, Item 222)
  - The Final Victory (Ballad No. 3) (Box 1, Item 223)
  - First March of the 202nd Regiment, Pa., Vols., in Dixie's Land (Box 1, Item [unnumbered])
  - Flag of Fort Sumter (Box 1, Item 224)
  - The Flag of Our Union (Box 1, Item 225)
  - The Flag of Our Union (Box 1, Item 226)
  - The Flag of Our Union (Box 1, Item 227)
  - The Flag of Our Union (Box 1, Item 228)
  - Flag of our Union Forever (Box 1, Item 229)
  - The Flag of the Free (Box 1, Item 230)
  - The Flag of the Free (Box 1, Item 231)
  - The Flag of the Republic (Box 1, Item 232)
  - The Flag With the Thirty Four Stars (Box 1, Item 233)
  - The Flag's Come Back to Tennessee! (Box 1, Item 234)
  - Flip Flap (Box 1, Item 235)
  - For the Union We'll Die (Box 1, Item 236)
  - Fourth of July Song (Box 1, Item 237)
  - Fourth of July Song (Box 1, Item 238)
  - Fourth of July Song (Box 1, Item 239)
  - A Fragment (Box 1, Item 240)
  - Free & Easy of our Union (Box 1, Item 241)
  - Free & Easy of our Union (Box 1, Item 242)
  - Free & Easy of our Union (Box 1, Item 243)
  - Freedom's Call (Box 1, Item 244)
  - Freedom's Guide (Box 1, Item 245)
  - Freedom's Guide (Box 1, Item 246)
  - Freedom's Guide (Box 1, Item 247)
  - Freemen, Rally! (Box 1, Item 248)
  - The French Lady (Box 1, Item 249)
  - The Friends We Leave Behind Us (Box 1, Item 250)
  - The Gallant Colonel (Box 1, Item 251)
  - The Gallant 99th Regiment. N.Y.S.V. (Box 1, Item 252)
  - Gallant Pennsylvania 69th, Irish Volunteers (Box 1, Item 253)
  - The Gallant 69th Regiment (Box 1, Item 254)
  - The Gallant Soldier (Box 1, Item 255)
  - The Gallant Soldier (Box 1, Item 256)
  - The Gallant Sons of Erin (Box 1, Item 257)
  - The Gallant 28th (Box 1, Item 258)
  - Gay and Happy (Box 1, Item 259)
  - Gay and Happy (Box 1, Item 260)
  - Gay and Happy (Box 1, Item 261)
  - Gen. Gilmore vs. Beauregard (Box 1, Item 262)
  - Gen. Grant's Victory at Chattanooga (Box 1, Item 263)
  - Gen. McClellan (Box 1, Item 264)
  - General Lee (Box 1, Item 265)
  - General Scott and Corporal Johnson (Box 1, Item 266)
  - Gen'l Sherman's Bonny Boys (Box 1, Item 267)
  - Gen. Siegel's Celebrated Camp Song (Box 1, Item 268)
  - The Girl I Left Behind Me (Box 1, Item 269)
  - The Girl I Left Behind Me (Box 1, Item 270)
  - Give Me a Noble Fellow With a Bucktail in His Hat (Box 1, Item 271)
  - Give Us Back Little Mac Our Old Commander (Box 1, Item 272)
  - Give Us Back Our Old Commander (Box 1, Item 273)
  - Give Us Back Our Old Commander (Box 1, Item 274)
  - Give Us Back Our Old Commander (Box 1, Item 275)
  - Give Us Back Our Old Commander (Box 1, Item 276)
  - The Glorious Flag of Liberty (Box 1, Item 277)
  - The Glorious Flag of Liberty (Box 1, Item 278)
  - Glorious 69th! (Box 1, Item 279)
  - The Glorious Stripes & Stars (Box 1, Item 280)
  - The Glorious Stripes & Stars (Box 1, Item 281)
  - Glory Hallelujah No. 1 (Box 1, Item 282)
  - Glory Hallelujah No. 2 (Box 1, Item 283)
  - Glory Hally, Hallelujah! or The John Brown Song (Box 1, Item 284)
  - Glory to God! Glory to God! (Box 1, Item 285)
  - God be our Trust (Box 1, Item 286)
  - God for our Native Land (Box 1, Item 287)
  - God Save the Union (Box 1, Item 288)
  - God Save the Union (Box 1, Item 289)
  - God Will Care for Mother Now (Box 1, Item 290)
  - God Will Care for Mother Now (Box 1, Item 291)
  - God Will Repay (Box 1, Item 292)
  - Good News from Home (Box 1, Item 293)
  - Good Ship Cumberland (Box 1, Item 294)
  - Good Will Hose Song (Box 1, Item 295)
  - The Goose Hangs High (Box 1, Item 296)
  - The Goose Hangs High No. 2 (Box 1, Item 297)
  - Gov. Hicks (Box 1, Item 298)
  - Grafted into the Army (Box 1, Item 299)
  - Grafted into the Army (Box 1, Item 300)
  - Grafted into the Army (Box 1, Item 301)
  - Grafted into the Army (Box 1, Item 302)
  - Grant's the Man (Box 1, Item 303)
  - Grant's the Man (Box 1, Item 304)
  - Hail! To the South (Box 1, Item 305)
  - Hail to the Union (Box 1, Item 306)
  - Hail to the Union (Box 1, Item 307)
  - Happy Land of Canaan (Box 1, Item 308)
  - Happy Land of Canaan No. 5 (Box 1, Item 309)
  - Happy Land of Canaan No. 5 (Box 1, Item 310)
  - Happy Land of Canaan No. 5 (Box 1, Item 311)
  - Happy Land of Canaan No. 6 (Box 1, Item 312)
  - Happy Land of Kanaan (Box 1, Item 313)
  - Hark! The Summons (Box 1, Item 314)
  - Hark! The Summons (Box 1, Item 315)
  - The Harp of Old Erin and Banner of Stars (Box 1, Item 316)
  - The Hearty Welcome Home (Box 1, Item 317)
  - Help Us Save the Union (Box 1, Item 318)
  - The Hero of Lexington (Box 1, Item 319)
  - Invalid Corps (Box 1, Item 320a)
  - He's Gone to the Arms of Abraham (Box 1, Item 320b)
  - The Hillhouse Infantry (Box 1, Item 321)
  - Hoist up the Flag, Long May it Wave (Box 1, Item 322)
  - Hoist up the Flag (Box 1, Item 323)
  - Hoist up the Flag, Long May it Wave (Box 1, Item 324)
  - Hoist up the Flag, Long May it Wave (Box 1, Item 325)
  - Hoist up the Flag (Box 1, Item 326)
  - Hoist up the Flag (Box 1, Item 327)
  - Hoist up the Flag (Box 1, Item 328)
  - Hold On Abraham! Uncle Sam's Boys are Coming Right Along (Box 1, Item 329)
  - Hold On Abraham! Uncle Sam's Boys are Coming Right Along (Box 1, Item 330)
  - A Holiday's Dream, After Too Much Egg Nog (Box 1, Item 331)
  - The Home Guards (Box 1, Item 332)
  - Home! The Boys are Marching (Box 1, Item 333)
  - How Are You? Conscript!! (Box 1, Item 334)
  - How Are You Conscript? (Box 1, Item 335)
  - How Are You Conscripts? (Box 1, Item 336)
  - How Are You, Greenbacks (Box 1, Item 337)
  - How Are You, Green-backs? (Box 1, Item 338)
  - How Are You, Green Backs? (Box 1, Item 339)
  - How Are You Hold Hingland (Box 1, Item 340)
  - How Are You Hold Hingland? (Box 1, Item 341)
  - How Are You, Maximilian? (Box 1, Item 342)
  - How Sherman's Veterans Took Atlanta (Box 1, Item 343)
  - How to Close This Cruel War (Box 1, Item 344)
  - A Hundred Years Hence (Box 1, Item 345)
  - A Hundred Years Hence (Box 1, Item 346)
  - Hunkey Boy is Yankee Doodle (Box 1, Item 347)
  - Hurra for our Union (Box 1, Item 348)
  - Hurrah for the Flag of the Free! (Box 1, Item 349)
  - Hurrah for the Land We Love! (Box 1, Item 350)
  - Hurrah! For the Union! (Box 1, Item 351)
  - Hurra for the Union! (Box 1, Item 352)
  - Hurra for the Union! (Box 1, Item 353)
  - Hurrah for the Land We Love (Box 1, Item 354)
  - The Hurrah! For the "Red, White, and Blue" (Box 1, Item 355)
  - Hurrah for Us (Box 1, Item 356)
  - Hymn for the National Funeral (Box 1, Item 357)
  - I Am Fighting for the Nigger (Box 1, Item 358)
  - I Am Not Sick, I'm over Forty-five (Box 1, Item 359)
  - I Cannot Support Him! Can You? (Box 1, Item 360)
  - I Dreamed My Boy Was Home Again (Box 1, Item 361)
  - I Loved that Dear Old Flag the Best (Box 1, Item 362)
  - I Loved that Dear Old Flag the Best (Box 1, Item 363)
  - I Want to be a Soldier (Box 1, Item 364)
  - I Want to be a Soldier! (Box 1, Item 365)
  - I Want to be a Soldier (Box 1, Item 366)
  - I Want to be a Soldier (Box 1, Item 367)
  - I'm Down on Double-Quick (Box 1, Item 368)
  - I'm Going to Fight Mit Sigel (Box 1, Item 369)
  - I'm Going to Fight Mit Sigel (Box 1, Item 370)
  - I'm Off for Charleston (Box 1, Item 371)
  - I'm Off for Charleston (Box 1, Item 372)
  - In Memoriam (Box 1, Item 373)
  - In Memoriam (Box 1, Item 374)
  - In Memoriam (Box 1, Item 375)
  - "In Memoriam" (Box 1, Item 376)
  - In Memory of Col. Ellsworth, Fire Zouaves (Box 1, Item 377)
  - Independence Day (Box 1, Item 378)
  - The Invalid Corps (Box 1, Item 379)
  - Irish Brigade (Box 1, Item 380)
  - The Irish Brigade No. 2 (Box 1, Item 381)
  - Irish Volunteer (Box 1, Item 382)
  - Irish Volunteer (Box 1, Item 383)
  - The Irish Volunteers (Box 1, Item 384)
  - The Irish Volunteers (Box 1, Item 385)
  - Is That Mother? (Box 1, Item 386)
  - Isn't it a Wonder? (Box 1, Item 387)
  - It Was My Mother's Choice (Box 1, Item 388)
  - It Was My Mother's Choice (Box 1, Item 389)
  - It Was My Mother's Voice (Box 1, Item 390)
  - Jackson's Requiem (Box 1, Item 391)
  - Jeff Davis (Box 1, Item 392)
  - Jeff Davis (Box 1, Item 393)
  - Jeff Davis (Box 1, Item 394)
  - Jeff Davis and His Uncle (Box 1, Item 395)
  - Jeff. Davis' Dream (Box 1, Item 396)
  - Jeff Davis' Dream (Box 1, Item 397)
  - Jeff. Davis in his Wife's Clothes (Box 1, Item 398)
  - Jeff Davis in the White House (Box 1, Item 399)
  - Jeff Davis or the King of the Southern Dominions (Box 1, Item 400)
  - Jeff Davis or the King of the Southern Dominions (Box 1, Item 401)
  - Jeff Davis's Proclamation (Box 1, Item 402)
  - Jeff in Petticoats (Box 1, Item 403)
  - Jeff. in Petticoats (Box 1, Item 404)
  - Jefferson "D" (Box 1, Item 405)
  - John Brown (Box 1, Item 406)
  - John Brown's Original Marching Song (Box 1, Item 407)
  - John Brown's Song (Box 1, Item 408)
  - John Bull, or Any Other Man (Box 1, Item 409)
  - John Bull, "Or Any Other Man" (Box 1, Item 410)
  - John C. Fremont, My Jo (Box 1, Item 411)
  - Johnny, Fill Up the Bowl! (Box 1, Item 412)